JERRY MARC T. HERMOSO

BACK-END WEB DEVELOPER / NODE JS DEVELOPER



+639665312570



jerrymarc.hermoso@gmail.com



251-D Prudencio St. Sampaloc, Manila



jerrycram21.github.io/marcportfolio

SUMMARY

Seeking out for new knowledge, with more than 4 years of working experience in back-end web development. Highly motivated and is able to work in a fast-paced highly demanding environment. Dedicated to building and optimizing user-focused websites for customers with various business objectives.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2017 - Present

Jr. Web Developer • SysNet Integrators, Inc.

- Designs, implements and monitors web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.
- Research new technologies and software packages for use in website projects.
- Have solid understanding of how web applications work including security, session management, and best development practices.
- Reviews code to validate structures and optimizes for speed and performance.
- Collaborates with in-house front-end developers to create sleek and innovative UI/UX.
- Collaborates with IT team, front-end, mobile developers, representing web team to establish project goals, projections and milestones.
- Creates relational database schema designs, with ability to code SQL queries, stored procedures, triggers, functions, indexing.
- Plans and engineers RESTful APIs to manipulate dynamic datasets on a project collaboration.
- Responsible for troubleshooting and issue analysis, as well as coding, testing and implementing web enhancements.
- Develops landing pages, dashboards, ride hailing application, live chat, online applications and REST APIs using Node.js-Express for web applications, MySQL/PostgreSQL for databases and AWS+NGINX for web server.

04/2016 - 05/2016

Web Page Designer(internship) • Rex Bookstore Head Office

Designed responsive web pages

References

- Bonifacio del Rosario Jr. (Senior Web Developer / Manager of Web Development Department) • mobile number available upon request.
- Ted Bagtas Jr. (Senior IT officer / Manager of Operation and Management Department) • mobile number available upon request.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (2013-2017)

UST Angelicum College, QC

SOFT SKILLS

- COMMUNICATION
- DILIGENT
- PROBLEM SOLVING
- PUNCTUAL
- ADAPTABILITY
- FAST LEARNER
- WILLINGNESS TO LEARN

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5 / CSS / JAVASCRIPT / ES6
- JQUERY / AJAX / DOM / BOOTSTRAP5
- NODE.JS / EXPRESS / NPM / JSON / EJS / HANDLEBARS.JS
- RESTFUL API / SOCKET.IO
- MYSQL / POSTGRESQL
- NGINX / AWS / PM2 / DOCKER
- WINDOWS / LINUX(UBUNTU)
- GIT / GITHUB / GITLAB
- MVC ARCHITECTURAL PATTERN
- MS VISUAL STUDIO CODE

AWARDS

- BEST THESIS AWARDEE
- 2-TIME DEAN'S LISTER
- 2-TIME ALPHA AWARDEE